<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Code03</string>
    <string name="article_title">Everything is made of something</string>
    <string name="article_subtitle">By Ajay Dasgupta</string>
    <string name="article_text">tyle How do you make tea? Simple , put a teaspoon of tea into a boiling keywordstyle
7 keywordstyle cup of water. Strain the water , pour some milk and sugar to taste keywordstyle
8 keywordstyle and the tea is ready! Interestingly , everything that we prepare haskeywordstyle
9 keywordstyle a recipe and is made up of simpler ingredients. keywordstyle
10 keywordstyle \n\nFor example , what is sugar made of? It is made of sugar keywordstyle
11 keywordstyle molecules , which in turn, are made up of atoms. The atom is the keywordstyle
12 keywordstyle building block of all substances. keywordstyle
13 keywordstyle \n\nThe concept of the atom was first introduced by the Greek keywordstyle
14 keywordstyle philosophers Democritus and Leucippus around 450-420 B.C. keywordstyle
15 keywordstyle The word \'atom\' comes from a Greek word that means \'indivisible\'. keywordstyle
16 keywordstyleInfact , until recently , the atom was considered to be indivisible.keywordstyle
17 keywordstyle \n\n<b><i>How small is an atom?</i></b> keywordstyle
18 keywordstyle \n\nAtoms are very tiny, with diameters like one keywordstyle
19 keywordstyle ten-thousand -millionth of a metre. So, approximately 50,000,000 keywordstyle
20 keywordstyle atoms of solid matter like iron, lined up in a row, would measure keywordstyle
21 keywordstyle one centimetre (0.4 inch). keywordstyle
22 keywordstyle\n\nHowever , Carl Sagan in his book Cosmos says that if you keywordstyle
23 keywordstylecut an apple -pie into equal halves and further divide each half keywordstyle
24 keywordstyleinto smaller and smaller pieces , in about 90 cuts you will reach keywordstyle
25 keywordstylea single atom. But, there is no knife that can cut so fine. keywordstyle
26 keywordstyleAnd the apple -pie would become invisible to the human eye in keywordstyle
27 keywordstyleabout 20 cuts. keywordstyle
28 keywordstyle \n\n<b><i>How do atoms create other substances?</i></b> keywordstyle
29 keywordstyle \n\nTwo or more atoms join together to form a molecule. keywordstyle
30 keywordstyle The molecule is the smallest part of a substance known as a keywordstyle
31 keywordstyle compound. For example , when two atoms of oxygen combine keywordstyle
32 keywordstyle with one atom of carbon , it forms carbon dioxide gas. keywordstyle
33 keywordstyle \n\nThese compounds group together to form bigger keywordstyle
34 keywordstyle complex substances. keywordstyle
35 keywordstyle \n\n<b><i>What are atoms made of?</i></b> keywordstyle
36 keywordstyle \n\nIs there a recipe for the atom? Yes! As with every other keywordstyle
37 keywordstyle thing , even the atom is composed of smaller particles. keywordstyle
38 keywordstyle These particles are called neutrons , protons and electrons. keywordstyle
39 keywordstyle They are necessary ingredients to make an atom. keywordstyle
40 keywordstyle \n\nScientists have also found substances which make up keywordstyle
41 keywordstyle electrons and protons. So we have a recipe for electrons and keywordstyle
42 keywordstyle protons as well. keywordstyle
43 keywordstyle \n\nEverything around us is actually made out of something keywordstyle
44 keywordstyle else, in an unending chain of ingredients and recipes. keywordsty</string>
</resources>
